<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Union Types :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/10-design-patterns-practices/5-union-types/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to continue talking about various types of entities, and subclasses, including union types. This is also somewhat of a subclass idea. Generally speaking with Union types, sometimes relationships are mutually exclusive, like we showed just a little bit ago, that can involve all sorts of things, right? Folders, with files, users groups, all of these things are mutually exclusive, right? A folder can be owned by a user or a group. But how would you prevent a folder from being owned by both types? Right? How would you prevent a folder from being owned by a user and a group, but it’s usually only only owned by one, right? It’s either owned by a particular user or owned by a group, but not both. So this is like a subclass. This is like a subclass. And this is a really big, a big representation here. So I’m actually going to switch screens here. And we are going to take a look at this inside of Lucid Chart. So this is a user folder and group. So in its base form, it’s going to be very difficult to actually represent the mutual exclusivity here. So a user can have zero or more folders, and a group can have zero or more folders. And here again, here, I’m combining some of my techniques here, right, here’s a self referencing table. So a folder belongs to another folder. And so that parent ID is indeed another folder. So here’s our self referencing fact. And then we have a name for it and group ID and user ID.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/10-design-patterns-practices/5-union-types/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>