<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SELECT FROM :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-1/3-1-2-single-table-queries-part-1-select-from/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Alright, so now that we have reviewed some of the basics, let’s go back to writing some actual queries. So we’ve already ran some basic select queries before, but we didn’t really break them down into into what each part actually contains. So we’ll start out first by looking at a select, but without the from clause. So the from clause is actually optional. But the Select is required. So this is the SQL syntax here. And I will show more things like this as we add more statements and elements to our SQL query. But this is about as basic as you can go. And then the square brackets there, that denotes an optional element. So the from clause is optional. But let’s without further ado, take a look at select select is the only thing required in a SELECT clause. So we don’t actually have to have a table to pull from, we can actually project data just without any initial data source, though usually, and the vast majority of queries you’ll actually use, we will have a From clause associated with the select. So you select these columns from this table, or from this data source, essentially was what that boils out to, can also rename the columns that we actually select. If our database design is done correctly, or done well, so to speak, we shouldn’t have to add a lot of aliasing here. But column alias aliases are really helpful when we are pulling data from multiple tables. And then also when we’re actually showcasing query results back to the actual user. Because a lot of times the database column names aren’t necessarily super user friendly. As far as in the user, it may be fine for a database engineer designer, but not so much for the end end result. I’ll showcase some aliasing here in just a second.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-1/3-1-2-single-table-queries-part-1-select-from/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>