<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Temporary Table Constructs :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/12-programmable-objects/2-temporary-table-constructs/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to continue our discussion on programmable objects. But in turn, we’re going to revisit some things that we’ve already covered around temporary tables. So, temporary table contracts are an important idea because as we get into programmable objects, like stored procedures, we need to understand that not everything that we do with SQL is physical storage, right? A lot of the times, this is logical representation. And in some cases, these are only logical to within within a certain session. So a single connection to the database, or global, which is available to everyone that is connected to the database added at any given time. So different things can be utilized in this sense. So things like things that we haven’t covered yet, our table types, so we can actually define our own custom types within SQL. And those can be made available. We’ve also we’ve done things like use CTE keys, and user defined functions as well, which we’ll also revisit here in just a few. But first off, we’re just going to cover mostly just variables and custom types. But let’s take a look at some examples of these variables that we’ve seen. So far. Most of the time that we’ve used them are scalar type data variables, right, we declare a variable, assign it a value, and then we utilize that as part of our SQL queries. But we can also create tables, and store those tables as a variable as well.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/12-programmable-objects/2-temporary-table-constructs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>