<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Derived Tables :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/2-derived-tables/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video, we’re going to be taking a look at derived tables. So derived tables are actually better known as a table valued sub queries. But with the restriction that a derived table can only be a self contained sub query, it cannot have any relation to the outer query or be a correlated sub query. So, derived tables are always going to be defined in the from clause and the outer of the outer outer query. But the scope of that is a little bit more restricted. So a derive table can only exist inside of as part of the outer query. So once that outer query is actually finished, that derive table no longer exists. But there are some other weird quirks with a derive table as well. And we have a couple different kinds of aliasing that we can utilize as part of this. And I’ll show both of these examples in line and external and what the differences will will be, we can actually also nest derived tables inside of each other. So we can just like what we can nest sub queries within sub queries and so on, we can also nest derive tables. But there are some limitations to these derive tables and use. So the primary limitation here is that inside of our FROM clause in the outer query, a derived table can only be operated on once. So that table can be referenced a single time as part of a join, and then it cannot be referenced again. So in isolation, so once that derived table has been joined with another, the original derive table can never be referenced again. So there is that primary limitation on the use of a derived table. But let’s take a look at a few examples here to see what these actually look like.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/2-derived-tables/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>