<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Closure Sets :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/7-closure-sets/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to get to our discussion on extracting more functional dependencies from our database. So before we ended on the Armstrong rules, which worked fairly well in pulling out more functional dependencies, but we found that it was a little bit tedious to actually do. And if we applied that to a much larger schema or much larger database becomes a little bit impractical and use. So that brings us to the idea of a closure set. So a closure set is defined as a set of attributes a one through a n, and the closure set of the that set of attributes is defined here, using this plus, right, so this is, if we have a one through a n with the curly brackets and the plus sign. That means this is the closure set of those attributes. The closure set of those attributes is the set of attributes b such that a one through a n implies E. So essentially, everything that you can imply for a given set of attributes, that is a closure set everything that we can imply from a set of attributes. So if we consider our previous example with name implies color category implies store and color category implies price to what are the closure set of these functional dependencies. So to start out, by computing the closure sets, we’ll list out each of the functional dependencies that we have. So name. So we’ll first start out with name. So what can we imply from name. So initially, we can just say, we can imply name and color, right name being the trivial implication, because we can name implies name. And we can get name and color, we can get color from our original functional dependency up here. So what about name and category? So what about name and category? So I’m just listing some of the individual attributes down here.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/7-closure-sets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>