<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Offset Window Functions :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/07-window-functions/4-offset-window-functions/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone, In this video, we’re gonna be taking a look at offset window functions. So our syntax is very similar to other window functions. So we have our function that we are going to apply over our window that is defined here. And remember, we can define our window using a partition. Without the partition, our window is going to encompass our entire query set, then we can order the rows within our window. And then we can also define which rows we are pulling, which are which rows are being applied to within that window. So we are primarily going to cover four different offset window functions here, these are going to differ a little bit when compared to offset fetch, which primarily just focused on pulling a top five or top 10 rows off of our query set, or, you know starting five rows. And instead of starting with the first row, we can do similar things with offset window functions. But in this case, the offsets are being applied by window instead of the entire query set. Although we can achieve identical results if our window is the entire query set, but we have four different functions here lag lead first value last value, first and last sound just as they are they obtained the first value inside of my window or the last value inside of my window. And then we also have lag and lead lag is going to be a before the current row and lead is after the current row. So whatever we’re looking at, we can lag in number of rows behind or lead in number of rows ahead. And we can calculate things based off of that which can be really beneficial in terms of things like running totals, these window functions, just like the previous ones that we covered are applied using the over clause and the offset window function, we are able to partition so we can define our window. Ordering is actually required, again, similar to what we saw with rank. And framing is also supported. But framing is only supported for first value and last value, not for lag and lead.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/07-window-functions/4-offset-window-functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>