<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction to Window Functions :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/07-window-functions/1-introduction-to-window-functions/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video series, we’re going to be taking a look at window functions. So with window functions, we’re actually going to be applying a function or an expression over a subset of rows from your query. And so the subset is actually referred to as the window. So hence the term window functions because we’re feeding the that small window of rows that saw a small subset of rows, and applying a function on top of that to calculate some value. But up to this point, we can actually accomplish some of this functionality using things like group by and sub queries. But window functions do allow us some added flexibility and some added expression that we can’t get otherwise. So when comparing this to group by, we can like said we can accomplish similar results, except for the fact that with group by we actually lose some of the detail, meaning that when we actually do the groupings, the all the rows that belong to a group, all those details are actually lost, because the only values that are retained are the columns that belong as part of the group. And of course, we can add the aggregates, as well. But all of the other details, the individual row information is not included as part of the grouping. Then we can also, with window functions, we can also calculate things across groups, were grouped by when we do aggregates, those aggregates belong to that group only. And so we can’t do an aggregate or calculations between groups where with window functions, we can achieve that functionality, similar ideas, similar story that we achieve with sub queries. But the primary benefit here with window functions with sub queries is that all of the the actual query that the underlying query, so in this case, like the outer query, all of those filters and rows are preserved. And so we don’t actually have to, to, to actually achieve some of the similar functionality. With sub queries versus window functions, we actually have to duplicate our sub query.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/07-window-functions/1-introduction-to-window-functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>