




  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
	  

  
	
		
		
	  

  
	
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Single Table Queries Part 3 :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/</link>
    <description> Predicates IN, BETWEEN, and LIKE Operator Precedence CASE Expression Variables Converting Data Types Character Data Types Date/Time Data Types </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 21:48:20 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Single Table Queries Part 3</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-1-single-table-queries-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-1-single-table-queries-part-3/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video series, we’re going to be taking our last look at single table queries, and primarily introducing some more operations and expressions that we can utilize as part of them, as well as a little bit of discussion on variables and different data types that we can work with. But before we work with that, let’s quickly review what we covered last time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CASE</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-2-single-table-queries-part-3-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-2-single-table-queries-part-3-case/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at the case statement in SQL. So the case statement is very, very much like the switch statements in Java, although in Python, they don’t have the language to have a switch statement. But just like a chained if else clause. So in its simple form, it’s going to compare scalar values, so like numbers and things like that, and return a value with its first match.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variables</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-3-single-table-queries-part-3-variables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-3-single-table-queries-part-3-variables/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to take a look at variables and SQL. So variables are a little bit different than compared to your normal programming languages, primarily just the way they syntax that they’re, that they’re declared their scope and things like that. And we’ll be covering variables briefly in this video. And then we’ll cover them a little bit more in depth as we get to more some more complicated SQL examples.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Character Types</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-4-single-table-queries-part-3-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-4-single-table-queries-part-3-text/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be exploring a little bit more into different data types in SQL. So this first bit is going to be mostly on just text. So text comes in a variety of a couple different forms and databases, little bit more so in SQL Server, but we have a fixed length type, so char, and then in char, so in char being Unicode type, and we’ll talk about that here in just a minute.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Date Time</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-5-single-table-queries-part-3-datetime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-3/3-3-5-single-table-queries-part-3-datetime/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone, this is going to be our last video for the single table queries part three series. And in this video, we’re going to be looking at some date time data types. There are a lot of different functions and functionality that you can leverage as far as date and date times, I’m not going to cover all of them, I will cover a few and explore a little bit more or have a little bit more and actual written notes, as well as links to official documentation for you to read through as well if you’d like to explore in a deeper sense.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>