<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joins :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 10:00:41 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Joins</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/1-introduction-to-joins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/1-introduction-to-joins/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video series, we’re going to be talking about joins with databases. So up to this point, we’ve focused on single table queries. But now we can start working on bringing in data from multiple, multiple tables and more or multiple data sources. joins, we’re going to be talking about overall in this set of videos, cross joins, Inner Joins, and pretty much variations of those. So the primary two types of joins that we’ll be focusing on our cross joins and inner joins. But we’ll also talk about outer joins as well here and a few. First, before we get into looking at multi table queries, let’s review what we’ve done so far. So first off, real big point, real big point to drive home here is the processing order. So remember, SQL is kind of different are kind of weird in comparison to the programming languages that you’re used to. So most programming languages are going to go from execute from top down, even when you’re working inside of individual functions. But with SQL, the the order of which that you actually program your query, and is going to be different from the order that that query is processed. Let’s remember that we don’t start off with the SELECT clause, we actually start with the from, so we have to know what our data sources first. And then we can filter those rows from those tables. Using the where clause, we can optionally group those rows up together based off of a certain number of columns or column expressions. And then we can actually also filter those groups. But remember, the having clause can only be used with the group by cuz having filters group by group, and remember, were filters row by row. So where can only be paired with from and having can only be paired with group by, then our select clause gets executed. So now we pick out which columns we want in our results. And then once our columns are selected, we can then determine distinct or not.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross Joins</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/2-cross-joins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/2-cross-joins/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone, In this video, we’re going to start taking a look at cross join. So cross joins are going to be the first join out of the three that we’re going to be covering. So on here, the syntax is listed on the slide. So from Table A cross join table B. And so the table source is listed here and a little bit of a generic sense, because the table source itself can actually be the result of another join. So let’s take a look at what cross joins involve. So cross joins are one of the simplest versions of a join between two tables. So it does have only one single processing phase. And that process, that processing phase is the Cartesian product. If you’ve never taken a look at a Cartesian product before, all, all we’re actually doing here is taking each row in table A and combining it with Table B, and then going down to the next. So row one with combined with each of the rows in table B and then row two and Table A each of the rows in table B and keep on going like that until we run out of rows in the first table. Now, the syntax here is listed in two different forms sequel 89, and SQL 92. And I’ll show examples of both. For this class. In general, I’m going to lean more towards one versus the other. But just be aware that there are two ways that we can actually list joins and our SQL queries. But nonetheless, let’s take a look at a cross join of the Cartesian product between two tables. And it’s a little bit easier to see this and an example.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inner Joins</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/3-inner-joins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/3-inner-joins/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back, everyone. So we’ve already started to take a look at some of the joints that are available to us and SQL. So the cross joins is what we first started with. But now we’re going to continue on and explore enter joints. Now, the syntax for an inner join is very similar to the cross join. So from Table A, and then enter, join table B on some condition. And do note that the inner part here is optional. So you can just say from table a join on Table B, generally speaking, I’m going to encourage leaving the keyword enter there. So again, it’s more obvious to which join we’re actually using. So what is an inner join. So inner joins are very similar to the cross join. And since that the first phase of an inner join is the cross join, so it produces the Cartesian product. So remember, the Cartesian product is all the different combinations of rows that you can make between the two tables. But with the inner join, we actually add a filtering phase along with that. So step two of the inner join is going to filter based off of whatever the predicate is, or the join, right, so join a table, a inner join table be on condition. So that predicate, that condition that we’re actually doing typically is going to be some, you know, column XYZ equals column ABC, or something like that, is probably the most common, but I’ll show some examples here in a few minutes. And again, there are two syntaxes that are supported here, SQL 89, and SQL 92. But again, I typically Lin, lean one towards one versus the other. And I’ll show the difference between the two here in just a few moments. Enter join here. So let’s see an example of this as a general table first.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join Variations</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/4-join-variation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/4-join-variation/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video, we’re going to be taking a look at some more complicated joins. So we’ve covered cross joins and Inner Joins so far. And remember, the inner join is just a cross join, but with a filter. But we haven’t really added a whole lot to these queries yet. So let’s take a look at a few different things that we can actually accomplish with them. In this video, we’re going to be talking a little bit about composite joints, where so far with our predicates that we included in our inner join us just enter join on one column. So our predicates are relatively simple. But we can actually have a little bit more complicated join there as well. So if we have table A and Table B, we can actually match those records on more than one column from each of the tables using Boolean operations. We can also join ourselves. So this sounds kind of weird at first, but there are a lot of good reasons where we would want actually want to join a table with itself in order to extract different kinds of relationships. And then we also have non equal joins, non equal joins are going to use an operator other than equality in inside of an inner join. So instead of matching, inner joining table a table B, where column one and Table A equals table, column one and Table B, maybe we have greater than or less than, or something like that. And then the last thing that we’re going to be working with today is going to be multi join queries. Now multi join queries are just as it sounds, right, we’re going to join more than two tables together. Now, we can actually mix and match joins as well. So we don’t just have to use all exclusively Inner Joins, or cross joins, or outer joins, which we’ll cover here later. But the big point here is that the join operations are executed from left to right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join Review</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/5-join-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/5-join-review/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at our last and final join outer joins. Outer Joins in particular have three different variations for left and right. But before we get into a new joint, let’s take a look at the material that we’ve covered so far. So last time, we covered a lot of cross joins and inner joins, which are both table operators, that we can utilize to have queries that pull from more than one table. Initially, we covered only tables that we’re pulling from just a single table. And so our FROM clause wasn’t very complicated. But then we learned we can use things like cross join an inner join, to pull from, you know, two, three, or even more different, different tables and join those all into one single table as a result, SQL Server in particular, supports four different table operators join, apply, pivot and pivot. For this class, we are only focusing on join in particular, but and join is the only standard operator anyways, apply pivot and Unpivot. You may not see in other SQL languages like my SQL and Postgres.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Outer Joins</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/6-outer-joins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/6-outer-joins/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone, this video, we’re gonna be taking a look at our last and final type of join the outer join. So here on the slide here actually shows some of the syntax that we’ve had so far, where we have our FROM clause. And we can join two different tables, two tables to and I say table source, because it doesn’t actually have to be a table from the database, right, it could be the result of a another join as well. So a table of some kind, joined with another table. So we’ve done the cross join, and we’ve done the inner join. And now we are going to do this outer join. This is this last syntax here. So we have a left, right or full outer join. And again, outer is going to be an optional key word, depending on ancy 89, or 92 syntax. But I’m going to encourage that outer be listed there, because it makes your queries significantly easier to read. But let’s take a look at what the OUTER JOIN actually contains with. So an outer join has three logical processing phases, instead of to write. So let’s take a look at what that what that looks like. So we have the Cartesian product, just like what we have with just like what we have with the cross join. And then just like the inner join, we Filter Rows out based off of some predicate. But in addition to that, we can now we now add rows from the preserved table. So what in the world is the preserve table? So fine line here is that the OUTER JOIN is just like an inner join, except with this extra third, this third processing step. So the reserved table is identified by either left, so the left table is preserved, right, or the right table is preserved or full. Both tables are preserved with us. And I’ll cover some more examples of this. Because this initially is kind of weird, like, what do I mean by a table being preserved? Well, I’ll explain that here in just a moment.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>