<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Limitations of BCNF Decomposition :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/12-bcnf-decomp-limits/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at some limitations behind decomposition using Boyce Codd Normal Form. So previously, we talked about how we, when we’re decomposing our tables, we need to be careful because if we’re not actually adhering to Boyce Codd Normal Form, and we’re decomposing our tables, ad hoc Li, we could actually have lossy decomposition, meaning we actually lose the original information, or at least, we lose, we don’t lose rows of data. But we can’t we can’t actually reconnect those rows of data together. So our joins become useless there. But there are some limitations behind Boyce Codd Normal Form. So Boyce Codd, normal form by itself and we’re decomposing according to it. Our decompositions are always lost less, which is a good thing, which is a good thing. But what about functional dependencies? So if we have this relation here, Professor projects departments, where we have our functional dependencies, Professor implies department and projects department implies professor. This is a Boyce Codd Normal Form violation because we do have a functional dependency. That is not a super key. Okay, so we want to decompose this. And so we have Professor departments, Professor department, and then we’ll have everything else, right, Professor department and everything else. So that’s Professor department, and we have Professor project. But what about this functional dependency here, Project department implies professor.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/12-bcnf-decomp-limits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>