<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Views &amp; User Defined Functions :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/12-programmable-objects/3-views-user-defined-functions/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking another look at views and user defined functions. So remember, a view is a logical construct only. And it is considered also a table expressions. So remember, views are just queries that we created and stored as part of our database. But the data that the view actually pulls from is not actually stored. Again, as part of the view, the view is nothing more than just a query that retrieves data from other tables. But it is a very useful construct, to allow users to interact with the database in a more secure way. Because they don’t have access to the they don’t have direct access to the original tables. Views in general, give a false sense of performance increase, even though views themselves have no benefit at all, towards performance of your of the queries that are actually executing. So I mean, views are very commonly misused in general, in terms in terms of databases. So a lot of times people get the false sense of performance increase. And a lot of times views are kind of abused in that way. And so we have to really do be careful when we’re working with working with views. Views, in general are a good way to abstract the database away, and to allow your users to interact with your database, and directly, but nonetheless, it’s not a bulletproof solution. So when when we actually use views, views are, as I mentioned, right, very easy to do securely.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/12-programmable-objects/3-views-user-defined-functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>