<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Database Relationship Types :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/10-design-patterns-practices/2-relationship-types/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a deeper dive into relationship types between our tables. And we’ve talked about some of these in passing before when we talked about UML diagrams. So we’ve seen these as part of the homework, and throughout our various other videos that we’ve had in this class so far. But let’s take a deeper dive into what these represents. So the first one that I’m going to cover here is one too many. And so the one of the common examples that you’ll see with this is a parent child type of relationship. So this is something where one record can have many connections on the right hand side, so one on the left many on the right, this can be something in the form of department, and employee. Or it could be something like our customer, and order, as we’ve seen so far in our database. And so the one to many representation here between these two entities would look something like this. So we would have, for our departments, we have, we’re one we have a department that can have one or more employees, an employee belongs to one and only one department. So the double dash here. So this, this here is going to represent one and only one. And then this here is one or many, then for our customer and order we have, we have one customer who has, who can have many orders. But a customer may not have an order yet, right. And we’ve seen this as part of our queries with the wide world importers database, where some customers or some salespeople don’t have any orders or or sales and a particular year, or even on a on any particular day, right. So that representation looks something like this, and a formal UML diagram. So we have our one and only one, zero or many, one and only one, one or many. But some of this here is logical constructs only, meaning that I can draw my relation here in my UML diagram. But some of this cannot be related cannot be physically represented as part of our database, and SQL Server Postgres, whatever database you’re actually working with, now, particularly this representation here, between department and employee.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/10-design-patterns-practices/2-relationship-types/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>