<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Database Design Example :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/2-database-design-example/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video, we’re going to be taking a look at an example database design. So we’ve shown some basic database, UML diagrams, but we really haven’t taken the time to draw our own yet. So in this example, we’re going to take a look at designing a really basic database for offering college courses on a campus like K State, a course is going to be defined by its number delivered by a department in a college and offered certain semesters at the same time on various days of the week. So this is going to be the basis that we’re going to start off of start from for drawing our database design. And here, I don’t really give a lot of details here, right, we’re just basically defining a college class, right, like cc 520. Right, CC is essentially the department, which is offered in the Arts and Sciences College. And so 520 is the number and typically right, the CC the department and number is going to be a unique combination within a given college. And so there’s a lot of other core details here that we’re missing as part of this. But let’s take a look at how we might start drawing a database that will store college courses. So what we have here is called Lucid Chart, it is a diagramming tool that can be found online, you can download it as well, there is a free version that I’m using here, it does limit you to the number of documents that you can actually create. But for the most part, you can get around that by adding multiple pages like I have down here to the same document, you can achieve the same kind of functionality through a lot of other programs. One other one that I really like is called draw.io, which is a completely free tool that you can use online to draw things like flowcharts. And in this case, UML diagrams for drawing or designing databases.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/2-database-design-example/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>