<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Except :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/08-sets/4-except/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video, we’re going to be taking a look at the Accept set operator. So accept is going to have similar syntax as we’ve seen so far. Again, input to query one on the left input query two on the right with the except operator in between, and an optional order by to end with. So what does the except operator actually do? So the except operator is going to be the difference between two sets. So the result is going to be everything. So a except B is going to be things that belong to a but not to be just like a subtraction operator, essentially. Except all does not exist, just like intersect all does not exist, and T SQL. So again, though, we can use a similar workaround that we’ve done with intersect all. But again, the default behavior for accept is accept distinct, so no duplicates. So what does our Venn diagram look like for the Accept set operator, so the Accept set operator works very much like our subtraction, right, so we have all of a except B, so A, but not B, if we’re talking in Boolean, so all of a but we exclude anything that anything of a that is shared with B. So if a value is in A and B, that value is removed, as part of this except set operator, let’s take a look at an example of this set operator being applied to two sets. So we’re going to draw out the set operator that are the sets that we had previously with Union and intersect. So this would be our one, two, and three for our first set, except which looks like our minus sign.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/08-sets/4-except/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>