<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BCNF Decomposition with Closure Sets :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/10-bcnf-decomp-closure/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at Boyce Codd Normal Form decomposition again. But instead of using functional dependencies for the basis of our decomposition, we’re going to use Closure sets. Now in general, I find closure closure sets to be a little bit more complicated to use for decomposition. So I typically lean on using functional dependencies as the basis for decomposing my tables and normalizing them. But closure sets can be a very consistent way to find all of our functional dependencies and therefore have a more guaranteed normalization results at the end. But I’ll show an example here in a little bit where the decomposition using Closure sets actually can generate more than one set of resulting tables. But what does the algorithm actually look like? So we have this is going to be like said, this is going to be a little bit complicated to rebel, try to read this, read this out slowly here. Find the x such that remember S T stands for such that. So find x such that x is not equal to the closure set. And the closure set is not equal to all attributes. So x is not a super key. And remember, x here is referring to a set of attributes, right? Just like what we had before, right, so x is a set of attributes. So if not found, then r is in Boyce Codd Normal Form. Okay. So this is essentially kind of work kind of going back to our like bad functional dependencies that we use last time to be composed. But here instead, functional dependency, that is not a super key. So let’s keep on breaking this down then. Okay. So if, if we did find a set of attributes, right, if we did find a set of attributes, that is not the full closure set, and not a super key, then let’s create a new set of attributes. That is the that is all attributes in the relation minus the closure set.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/10-bcnf-decomp-closure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>