<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outer Joins :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/6-outer-joins/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone, this video, we’re gonna be taking a look at our last and final type of join the outer join. So here on the slide here actually shows some of the syntax that we’ve had so far, where we have our FROM clause. And we can join two different tables, two tables to and I say table source, because it doesn’t actually have to be a table from the database, right, it could be the result of a another join as well. So a table of some kind, joined with another table. So we’ve done the cross join, and we’ve done the inner join. And now we are going to do this outer join. This is this last syntax here. So we have a left, right or full outer join. And again, outer is going to be an optional key word, depending on ancy 89, or 92 syntax. But I’m going to encourage that outer be listed there, because it makes your queries significantly easier to read. But let’s take a look at what the OUTER JOIN actually contains with. So an outer join has three logical processing phases, instead of to write. So let’s take a look at what that what that looks like. So we have the Cartesian product, just like what we have with just like what we have with the cross join. And then just like the inner join, we Filter Rows out based off of some predicate. But in addition to that, we can now we now add rows from the preserved table. So what in the world is the preserve table? So fine line here is that the OUTER JOIN is just like an inner join, except with this extra third, this third processing step. So the reserved table is identified by either left, so the left table is preserved, right, or the right table is preserved or full. Both tables are preserved with us. And I’ll cover some more examples of this. Because this initially is kind of weird, like, what do I mean by a table being preserved? Well, I’ll explain that here in just a moment.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/04-joins/6-outer-joins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>