




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Transactions and Indexes on CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/index.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Transactions and Indexes on CC 520 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Indexes</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/1-indexes/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/1-indexes/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription What are indexes? So, this is a topic that I, I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned indexes in passing a couple times in class, but we never really talked about what they do. Indexes are going to allow are really what allow the really fast lookups for your data. So anytime you have a let&amp;rsquo;s traditionally, by default, if you do not specify an index, most of the time, your index is going to be your primary key.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transactions &amp; Concurrency 1</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/2-transactions-concurrency-1/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/2-transactions-concurrency-1/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Let&amp;rsquo;s check out transactions. So as I mentioned before, transactions are kind of like a receipt for any of the queries that you actually execute for your database. Typically, if you&amp;rsquo;re working with data that is just on your local database transactions are a little bit overkill, it must that data is actually very sensitive. And then transactions are needed to prevent any loss of data in transit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transactions &amp; Concurrency 2</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/3-transactions-concurrency-2/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/3-transactions-concurrency-2/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription We&amp;rsquo;re gonna do a class activity today. And so what you need to do this is on the lecture 27 transactions and concurrency, you just need to download the transactions in currency dash participate dot SQL, zoom in here. So the transactions and currency dash participate dot SQL, that&amp;rsquo;s the one you need. And it will look like this. So this is the participate dot SQL file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transaction Log</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/4-transaction-log/index.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/14-transactions-and-indexes/4-transaction-log/index.html</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription This topic I&amp;rsquo;m going to be mostly skimming through, it&amp;rsquo;s important to be aware of, but not, I&amp;rsquo;m not really going to be testing on it. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a, what happens underneath the hood sort of thing. So we talked about transactions last time, right? Transactions are a essentially a receipt for any, any SQL that we actually execute on our database, including selects, updates, inserts, and deletes.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>