<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Multiple Path Problem :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/10-design-patterns-practices/7-multi-path-problem/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video, we’ll be talking about the multi path problem. So we’ve already talked about multi way relationships where we have multiple relationships between one or more tables. But the multiple path problem can come out of this type of relationship. So when there is more than one path between a single entity to another, we get an issue, right? This provides multiple different ways to do our joins, when we write our SQL queries, and when we have multiple ways of performing our joins when writing our queries, we can actually get different results depending on which direction we actually started joining first. So this provides an issue, right, because if we if we aren’t aware of this issue ahead of time, this provides an interesting problem that our queries are not going to provide consistent results, depending on which direction we start to join first. So there are a couple ways we can fix this issue. The first one is going to be taking out the foreign key reference entirely. And this makes it so that the person who is writing the query only has one and only one option to joining the tables together, right. So if there aren’t multiple ways of joining the same information together, then there’s not going to ever be the inconsistent issue with results. And so the problem here, though, attributes from the reference table would have to be duplicated in order to get that relationship across. The second option, second solution here is going to be duplicating the key and then use composite foreign keys instead, by using composite foreign keys, then no matter which direction we actually join, the results will always be the same, the result is always going to be the same. And so in this, I’m going to show a couple different examples of this, it’s all going to be based off of the same, the same set of tables, but I’ll show it in UML first, and the issue where where it arises. And then I’ll show an example in SQL as well. So here are two examples, right. So the first one on the left, right, this side, this is the multi path problem over here. And then it is fixed. Oops. On the right hand side, I fixed the multi path problem. And so let’s take a look at some of the distinct differences between the two. But first, I’m going to highlight why a multi path problem exists.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/10-design-patterns-practices/7-multi-path-problem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>