<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Functional Dependency Examples :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/5-fd-examples/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at some examples of functional dependencies. So first we’ve talked about when a functional dependency may hold officially as part of a relation. So a functional dependency holds or doesn’t hold on an instance of a relation or table. If for all cases are all rows, and that functional dependency holds true, or we find a row, that’s where a row where that functional dependency does not hold true. So we have this example bit of information. Here we have column student id, name, phone and department. And let’s say for the sake of this example, we say that our student ID in informs us that we know we can infer name, phone and department from just the student ID. So if we have a computer science students, we can say that that computer, we, if we have their ID, we can infer their name, and the phone number and department that they belong to. Let’s say we also can say that if we know the department, then we also know the phone number for that department. So let’s see if if these things hold true here. Well, if we look down the student ID column, this holds true right student ID implies name, phone and department because if I look at student ID, all of the bits of information, name, phone and department are unique for every single student ID. So we have no duplicated information, right? So if, for example, though, if both of these students here student ID, 3542 and 1111. If both of them had the same name, then we would have some issues, right, our functional dependency would not hold, because there would be no way for us to tell the two apart. So let’s continue on looking at some of these. So department phone, well, math holds true. So math implies 1234. And g implies 1234. Cis implies 9876 97. Six, that’s consistent.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/09-obtaining-good-design/5-fd-examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>