<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Intersect :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/08-sets/3-intersect/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video, we’re going to be taking a look at our next set operator intersect. So the the query syntax is very similar to what we’ve seen so far, we have an input query on the left and input query on the right the set operator in between, and an optional order by at the end. But do note that intersect does not have an intersect all option. So let’s take a look at what the intersect actually does. So the intersection between two sets results in the elements that are shared between the two sets. So the elements in B and the elements in A that are shared, that is what is left after the intersect actually fully happens. Now, as I mentioned, the intersect itself does not have an intersect all in T SQL, although we can do a little bit of a workaround here to get that to happen, if that is something that is needed. But let’s take a look at how this works with our Venn diagram. So intersect works very much like the end operator in Boolean algebra. So if we had a and b, we had the things that A and B shared. So for intersect A intersect B is going to result in a set such that the values and set that are in set A and in set B are returned. And we can actually also draw a Another similar example of we as we did with Union. So let’s get that going to have a set one, two, and three here, intersect a set that has three, four, and five, which will result in a set where that only has the numbers that are shared between sets A and B. So only three. All right, so we just did union here just a little bit ago. And let’s take a look at what this looks like with intersect. And I’ll be using the same exact, mostly the same exact query throughout all of my union examples just so it’s a little bit more consistent. So this is the exact same query that I ran with Union, except now we have intersect in between. And remember, the order of operations here is the input query one, followed by input query two, and then the intersect operation between the results of those two queries.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/08-sets/3-intersect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>