




	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		

	
	
		
		
		

	
	
		
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Table-valued Expressions on CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Table-valued Expressions on CC 520 Textbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 10:53:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Table-valued Expressions</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/1-introduction-to-table-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/1-introduction-to-table-expressions/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video series, we&amp;rsquo;re gonna be taking a look at table expressions. So previously, we talked about sub queries, particularly two types of sub queries self contained and correlated, the self contained sub queries being a sub query that can actually execute in isolation, so on its own without any dependency with the outside query. correlated query is the opposite of that, where we are referencing at least one attribute or column, and the inner query from the outer query.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derived Tables</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/2-derived-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/2-derived-tables/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be taking a look at derived tables. So derived tables are actually better known as a table valued sub queries. But with the restriction that a derived table can only be a self contained sub query, it cannot have any relation to the outer query or be a correlated sub query. So, derived tables are always going to be defined in the from clause and the outer of the outer outer query.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common Table Expressions</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/3-common-table-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/3-common-table-expressions/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be taking a look at common table expressions, otherwise known as CTS. We can see the syntax of a common table expression here on this particular site here, but it&amp;rsquo;ll show some examples that will make this a little bit easier to read. So, as I mentioned, common table expressions are also known as C, T E&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Views and Inline Table-valued Functions</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/4-views-and-inline-table-valued-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/4-views-and-inline-table-valued-functions/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be taking a look at views and table valued functions. And so up here I have both of the syntax for each. So have the syntax for review and the syntax for inline table valued functions. And I will show the Show More examples of these and will hopefully make a little bit more sense then views and inline table valued functions are provide an extra benefits when compared to derive tables and CTS.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Apply Operator</title>
      <link>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/5-apply-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ksu-cs-textbooks.github.io/cc520-sql-server-textbook/06-table-expressions/5-apply-operator/</guid>
      <description>YouTube Video Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And this video, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be taking a look at the Apply operator. So this is going to be our last table expression that we&amp;rsquo;re going to be looking at for this course. But again, the general syntax of the Apply operator is included up here. But I will of course, show some examples of how that looks. But what is the Apply operator.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>