<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Table-valued Expressions :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/</link>
    <description></description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 12:35:03 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Table-valued Expressions</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/1-introduction-to-table-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/1-introduction-to-table-expressions/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video series, we’re gonna be taking a look at table expressions. So previously, we talked about sub queries, particularly two types of sub queries self contained and correlated, the self contained sub queries being a sub query that can actually execute in isolation, so on its own without any dependency with the outside query. correlated query is the opposite of that, where we are referencing at least one attribute or column, and the inner query from the outer query. So we also talked about three different types of return values for sub queries that being single valued and multi valued. So those are the two primary ones that we covered. We also briefly talked about table valued returns. So remember, the single valued query is just as it sounds right, one single value that’s actually returned, so like a number or a string of some kind. And then multivalued sub queries are ones who are going to return one single column, but more typically more than one row. So technically, a single valued return is also a multivalued return. But a multivalued return can have more than one value, right? More than one row. But what if we have more than one column. So we really didn’t talk too much about what happens when a sub query returns more than one column. But that’s going to be our focus for today. So a query that or a sub query that returns more than one column is going to be commonly referred to as a table expression.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derived Tables</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/2-derived-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/2-derived-tables/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video, we’re going to be taking a look at derived tables. So derived tables are actually better known as a table valued sub queries. But with the restriction that a derived table can only be a self contained sub query, it cannot have any relation to the outer query or be a correlated sub query. So, derived tables are always going to be defined in the from clause and the outer of the outer outer query. But the scope of that is a little bit more restricted. So a derive table can only exist inside of as part of the outer query. So once that outer query is actually finished, that derive table no longer exists. But there are some other weird quirks with a derive table as well. And we have a couple different kinds of aliasing that we can utilize as part of this. And I’ll show both of these examples in line and external and what the differences will will be, we can actually also nest derived tables inside of each other. So we can just like what we can nest sub queries within sub queries and so on, we can also nest derive tables. But there are some limitations to these derive tables and use. So the primary limitation here is that inside of our FROM clause in the outer query, a derived table can only be operated on once. So that table can be referenced a single time as part of a join, and then it cannot be referenced again. So in isolation, so once that derived table has been joined with another, the original derive table can never be referenced again. So there is that primary limitation on the use of a derived table. But let’s take a look at a few examples here to see what these actually look like.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common Table Expressions</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/3-common-table-expressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/3-common-table-expressions/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at common table expressions, otherwise known as CTS. We can see the syntax of a common table expression here on this particular site here, but it’ll show some examples that will make this a little bit easier to read. So, as I mentioned, common table expressions are also known as C, T E’s. They’re very similar to derive tables write, similar in nature that the scope is limited to the outer query. But the benefit of a CTE is all of these things here. So probably the biggest benefits between a CTE and a derived derived table is that we can reference a CTE more than once. So previously, when we talked about derived tables, we, we were shown a derived table cannot be referenced more than once. So we can’t do a self join, for example, on a derived table, but with a CTE, that’s going to be possible. Along with derive tables, we can also do in line and external ABC and CTS, we can also utilize more than one CTE in the same query. And CTE is can also be recursive. We’re going to save recursive CTE, though, for a nother video, that’s a more complicated topic. But just like you can call and reference a function within a function, we can have a CTE that references itself. So recursion, but nonetheless, let’s take a look at a few examples of a CTE.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Views and Inline Table-valued Functions</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/4-views-and-inline-table-valued-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/4-views-and-inline-table-valued-functions/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at views and table valued functions. And so up here I have both of the syntax for each. So have the syntax for review and the syntax for inline table valued functions. And I will show the Show More examples of these and will hopefully make a little bit more sense then views and inline table valued functions are provide an extra benefits when compared to derive tables and CTS. So when we were using CTS and derived tables Previously, we had to use them within the same outer, the outer query, right, so the the life of a derive table or a CT exists only within the query, it actually executes. Otherwise, that CTE or derive table doesn’t actually exist. So views and inline table valued functions have a much broader scope. And so they provide the benefit that these are actually stored in the database itself. And so we can reference these in multiple queries in multiple occasions without having to recreate them every single time. So that’s the primary benefit here. So they’re available and stay in the database until they’re actually directly dropped from it. So you can really think of these are, from a view, it’s mostly just similar to a derive table, that we can actually reference more than once. And then similar to inline table functions, we can reference those more than once as well. But we can actually pass parameters to them. So they start to behave exactly as they sound, they start to behave more like functions than just something that we can call. So view is basically a function without parameters.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Apply Operator</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/5-apply-operator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/06-table-expressions/5-apply-operator/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And this video, we’re going to be taking a look at the Apply operator. So this is going to be our last table expression that we’re going to be looking at for this course. But again, the general syntax of the Apply operator is included up here. But I will of course, show some examples of how that looks. But what is the Apply operator. So apply itself is non standard syntax apply is unique to SQL Server, if you are looking in other SQL based languages, you’ll be looking for what is called a lateral join. But SQL Server calls this the apply operation. But in general, how this operates is apply as a table value a table operator, and so your the left and right hand side need to be table expressions. Or rephrase that. On the left hand side, we must have an actual table and the right hand side of the Apply can actually be a table expression. So it could be a CTE, it could be a T provided sub query or or anything alike, but some table expression on the right hand side. Now, the main benefits that we get out of using the apply or otherwise known as the lateral join, it allows us to do a join on a correlated sub query, right.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>