<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Merge :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/11-data-modification/5-merge/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at the MERGE statement as part of our data modification video series. So what data modification, remember, we’ve covered so far inserts, updates, and delete. But now we’re going to look at a way to combine those operations, The MERGE statement is going to allow you to both insert and update in a single statement. So the syntax is a little bit more complicated here. So we as follows We have merge and then the table that we’re targeting, and then using the source table, so let’s take a look at the syntax for merge. So the syntax here is a little bit more complicated than some of the other statements that we’ve seen so far. But we’ll go through some examples and see how it looks. But merge on the target table. So we’re merging two, using this table on this predicate. And so when this predicate finds a match, right when matched, do this, when not matched, do this. So we can do an update or delete here when matched or not matched, and vice versa, when matched, and when not matched are optional statements. So these are optional, but we’ll show some examples of how this works. And General. The statement here can include predicates for evaluating matches. This is mostly for verifying if changes actually happened as a result of some operation. And note that I’m actually saying matched here. For my predicate, we have this on keyword which is very similar to what we did with joins, right, and inside of a join that was defining the filter. But here, we’re not actually filtering any rows out, it’s determining whether or not a row matches or does not match the predicate. But it’s not necessarily filtering rows. So the operation is slightly different. But let’s take a look at an example of what merge looks like. So again, also, please make sure before, if you’re following along here, please make sure you run the setup query for the this video. And then let’s take a look at our first example. So I’m actually going to use a CTE here, to showcase this. So with CTE, this is just pulling out the information about Marie Jones.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/11-data-modification/5-merge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>