<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rank Window Functions :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/07-window-functions/2-rank-window-functions/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone, In this video, we’re going to be taking a look at rank window functions. So this is the first out of the three types of window functions that we’ll be covering. And you can see the syntax here, where we have our general function. So we have our function here over. And we have three different options that we’ll we can include as part of our window, our of our over clause. So partition, which is going to define how we group our window, our rows into our windows, order by is the ordering of the rows within those windows. And then we have the rows clause, which is the framing portion here. And so that’s how we define what rows inside of the window we actually include, as part of that we include to apply to our window function. So in our case, what we’re going to focus on in this video here is what kind of functions that we can apply here on the left hand side of the over clause. So for ranking window functions, we have four primary functions that we’ll utilize here, we have rank, DENSE RANK, row number and n tile. So rank and dense rake, operate mostly the same. So it’ll rank the rows within a window. So starting out, typically, like 1234, with with the rows inside, now, rank is a true ranking system. And then if there is a tie, the rank, the numbering system actually skips the number. So if we have a tie, for third place, for example, will it’ll go 123. And let’s say there’s a two way tie for three, it’ll skip four, and then go to five, and also show an example here in a few minutes. DENSE RANK is a little bit different in that matter, where DENSE RANK is actually not going to skip those numbers. And so with DENSE RANK, you’ll actually see, three show up twice. For example, if we had a two way tie for three, where rank would actually skip the number, row number is going to just be a sequential number within side inside of the window. So rank is not necessarily going to be a straight 1234, depending on if we have time ties, for example, or depending on what we’re actually ranking on, right. So if we’re ranking on sales, right, the person who has, let’s say, the highest sales is going to go is going to be rank one, and the lowest sales is going to be the last rank, where as the row number isn’t necessarily going to be correlated to that particular value. So just a straight sequential numbering.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/07-window-functions/2-rank-window-functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>