<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction to Subqueries :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/05-subqueries/1-introduction-to-subqueries/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video we’re going to be focusing on sub queries. Now up to this point, we’ve covered how to do single table queries. Multi table queries with join. So Inner Joins cross joins outer joins. But in this video, we’re going to be focusing on how we can nest queries inside of each other. But before that, let’s review a few things. Remember our processing order of SQL and the order that we write SQL is different. So the way we have to write SQL uses order of statements is listed here. But they’re processed, starting from the from clause, because before we can actually enter any of the other phases, we have to know what data to start with. Where allows us to filter those filter that data row by row, then we can of course, group that data together, and then filter those groups. So we have a the where clause being a row by row filter, the having clause being grouped by group filter, and then we can finally pick out which columns that we are projecting out and into our results, we can specify that we only want distinct rows from the from the result and also remember, distinct can also be utilized as part of aggregate functions as well, like Distinct Count, or count distinct sorry, then we can order our results as well as sending or descending order, ascending by default. And then finally, we can use top to restrict the number of rows that’s actually returned. So let’s say top five or top 5%. Offset fetch is the SQL standard of top remember, top is only native to Microsoft SQL Server. Fetch and offset are ancy standard and will be present in most SQL languages that you encounter.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/05-subqueries/1-introduction-to-subqueries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>