<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Single Table Queries Part 2 :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/</link>
    <description>HAVING ORDER BY DISTINCT TOP OFFSET…FETCH… Logical Processing Order</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 21:48:20 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Single Table Queries Part 2</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/3-2-1-single-table-queries-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/3-2-1-single-table-queries-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video series, we’re going to continue our talk on single table queries. Now last time, we covered a lot about the SELECT clause, which can be paired with from to choose which tables you’re picking from, and the where clause, which can filter which rows are being picked. And then we also did a little bit with group by and the having clause which filters those groups. So we’ll review those a little bit today. And then we will cover order by distinct Top Offset fetch, and also the process or the order in which those are logically processed inside SQL. So let’s first start out with the having clause, this is what we ended up on in the previous video. So remember, the having clause is a post group filter, right? So meaning the having clause can be used with in place of the where clause which filters row by row. So we have SELECT FROM WHERE, so the from clause picks which tables, so the data source, and then the where clause will filter out any rows that you don’t want. And but where clauses only row by row, likewise, so having is grouped by group, so having an were cannot be used interchangeably. So having can’t be used to filter out rows, or individual rows, and the where clause can’t be used to filter out groups. So that’s why they are separate there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DISTINCT</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/3-2-2-single-table-queries-part-2-distinct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/3-2-2-single-table-queries-part-2-distinct/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back, everyone. So let’s continue diving into adding more and more elements into our single table queries. In this video, we’re going to cover the distinct qualifier. So distinct allows us to guarantee uniqueness and the things that actually come out and are result of our query. So by default, we select all things. So all of the values inside of each of the columns that we actually pick. Now, when we use distinct, each of the columns that we specify to be distinct, we verify that those records are unique. So if we have five color, five rows that have the color blue, but if we only want the distinct records, those records that have duplicates will be removed from our result. So like aggregates, all is the default of our select, if distinct, is not specified. So when we do select orders, select star from orders, or select whatever from whatever table source that you have, by default, we’re pulling all of those records out. But if we add distinct in there, we actually guarantee you that each record is unique. So when we add that distinct, each of the tuples or, or the resulting set, it has only unique values.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TOP Results</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/3-2-3-single-table-queries-part-2-top/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/3-2-3-single-table-queries-part-2-top/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we are going to take a look at how we pick certain specify the number of rows that we actually want to return. And this is without the actual where filter and things like that all the even though, we can actually include that. So the first one that we’re going to talk about here is top. Now, top is not standard in SQL, you will only find it in certain database management systems. For example, SQL Server actually has the top keyword or top filter, I will talk about the anti standard here in just a minute. But top filters are rows based on order. So you can say, let’s say I want the top five rows by my results. And so based off of the ordering of the results, it will take the first x or n number of rows from it. So if I did top five, it gives me the top five rows. So you say top and then there’s, you specify the number or using an expression that you want to pick. And then you can specify whether you want the top in rows, or top in percent rows, right.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OFFSET-FETCH</title>
      <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/3-2-4-single-table-queries-part-2-offset-fetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/03-single-table-queries/03-single-table-queries-part-2/3-2-4-single-table-queries-part-2-offset-fetch/</guid>
      <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. So in this video, we are going to take a look at the offset fetch filter. So the offset fetch filter is the anti standard, equivalent to talk. So before we cover top, but top is going to only be specific to a certain set of database management systems. A SQL Server, for example, supports the top command. But not all, SQL is created equal. But offset fetch is standard. So you’ll find it in the majority of database languages that implement SQL. So that’s a benefit there. But the there is a little bit of a difference here. So top itself doesn’t actually support an offset. Although as offset fetch sounds like it does support that so we can offset by in number of rows. So if we want to skip a certain set certain number of rows, we can do that with the offset. And then we the fetch part is more similar to the top command, where we fetch n number of rows from our SQL results, right? Again, though, this is a filter that is determined that is based off of the ordering of our results.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>