<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Applications &amp; Databases :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/13-databases-and-applications/1-apps-and-databases/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. In this video, we’re going to be talking about how we might use a database and programming application to use it. And first off as well, I do apologize for my voice. I’m kind of losing it today. But please bear with me, as we get through this things that we’ve covered. So far, we’ve covered quite a few things, running from single table and multi table queries, updates, deletes, and a lot of things in between. The last big topic that we talked about were routines. And we’ve seen quite a few different types of routines as well. So we’ve seen user defined functions, stored procedures, triggers, but stored procedures are really going to be our primary focus, when we’re working with databases, applications, primarily because stored procedures do encapsulate some of the logic behind some of the queries. So if you happen to be a developer or software engineer, and not a database designer, or database engineer, you’re going to be able to actually work with the database without having to actually write the queries. And so that provides a lot of flexibility. So you have your database administrators writing the sequel and the stored procedures. And then you have your software engineers who are developing the application logic that connect with that stored procedure. And a lot of that provides a little bit of extra security as well, because we can actually lock down stored procedures to certain people. And it allows us to do some error handling inside of our stored procedure. But remember, we’re not going to want to do a lot of error handling on the database side, a lot of that is going to be handled by our application. And in some scenarios, stored procedures do provide a little bit of performance benefit, when compared to things like user defined functions, and views, things that we can actually access from an application. And our database, includes tables views, SQL commands, stored procedures, and overall stored procedures, again, are recommended in most scenarios here. Views are useful in certain situations, but again, they’re just encapsulating some of the logic and abstracting some of that away, and you don’t actually get much performance benefit.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/13-databases-and-applications/1-apps-and-databases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>