<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aggregate Window Functions :: CC 520 Textbook</title>
    <link>https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/07-window-functions/3-aggregate-window-functions/</link>
    <description>Video Transcription Welcome back everyone. And in this video, we’re going to be taking a look at aggregate window functions, aggregate window functions are going to have similar syntax as previous window functions. So you have the function applied over and then we can specify and define our windows that the function is being applied over the window being defined using the partition by clause, order of the rows within that window. And then which rows within that window are actually where what the function is actually being applied to. So we have a variety of different aggregate window functions. Typical the typical aggregate functions that we used as part of our previous sequel experiences apply just the same. So all of the group, all the experience that we have writing group by statements, so max, min, average count, some, all those sorts of things will apply here with aggregate window functions, although distinct is one of the clauses that are qualifiers that is not allowed as part of an aggregate window function. Although you can do a simple workaround here that will will show so as part of our aggregate window function, what is actually supported. So using the over clause, we can actually utilize both all three partitioning, ordering and framing as a result. So none of these are we can have all of these, or actually none of them for aggregate window functions, which is a really powerful, expressive way of utilizing these, the use cases for aggregate window functions are probably more common when compared to the other types of window functions. Although I would probably rank, you know, Agria as being the most common, and then you have rank and then offset. But aggregate window functions are very useful for things like running totals, period totals or quartile, things like that. So monthly totals year to date totals, moving averages, all of those calculations that require subdividing our results and things that we apply our functions on to. But nonetheless, let’s take a look at some examples of these inaction. So I have a quite a large query up here. Our CTE that we have been using so far, and our window function examples is the same thing here, we just have our order total CTE. But I also have an additional column here that I did last time I have salesperson ID, along with the Order ID, but I don’t have customer here. Now, if I go back down here to my actual query that’s utilizing utilizing the CTE, we have a salesperson order ID order total.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://textbooks.cs.ksu.edu/cc520/07-window-functions/3-aggregate-window-functions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  </channel>
</rss>